TIM SHAFFER

Douglassville, PA 19518 | Email: timothy.c.shaffer@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shaffer-tim | Github: https://github.com/Tim-Shaffer Portfolio: https://tim-shaffer.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer experienced in complex software development in the healthcare industry. Proven track record of completing simultaneous development and update projects on time and within budget to exceed expectations. History of mentoring and training others in best practices.

Skills

Languages: SQL | HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript

Applications: JQuery | Bootstrap | Firebase | Node.js | MySQL | Express.js | GIT Source Control **Soft Skills:** Agile Development | Software Development Lifecycle | Requirements Gathering |

Team Leadership | Complex Problem-Solving | Testing and Debugging |

Project Documentation | Customer Support | Microsoft Tools

PROJECTS

Star Wars RPG | https://github.com/Tim-Shaffer/unit-4-game | https://tim-shaffer.github.io/unit-4-game/StarWarsRpg.html

- Interactive Role Play Game to feature dynamically updated HTML pages using jQuery.
- Sole developer on this project.
- Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ¡Query

Feed Homer RPG | https://github.com/Tim-Shaffer/unit-4-game | https://tim-shaffer.github.io/unit-4-game/FeedHomer.html

- Interactive Role Play Game to feature dynamically updated HTML pages using jQuery.
- Sole developer on this project.
- Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery

Travel with the Team | https://github.com/Tim-Shaffer/TeamTravel | https://tim-shaffer.github.io/TeamTravel/

- A collaborative project that uses multiple API calls to present a team schedule and other activities happening in the same city as a scheduled game.
- Lead Developer on the project keeping the group on task while working on the API call to the scheduling site.
- Built using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, and moment.js

EXPERIENCE

Cerner Corporation Malvern, PA

2015 - 2019

Associate Lead Software Engineer (2018 – November 2019)

Wrote and configured code for new and upgraded solutions in accordance with technical specifications.

- Established a new process for reporting healthcare statistics to the state agencies of SC and PA out of Millennium Revenue Cycle, allowing the clients to avoid thousands of dollars in fines and to be listed as compliant.
- Created technical documentation in a wiki to promote the education and training of less experienced team members.
- Communicated with customers about progress updates, gathered feedback and worked to resolve specific concerns.

Senior Software Architect

(2016 - April 2018)

Ensured that quality applications were developed to meet specified business needs through software design and code quality.

- Collected and defined customer requirements and moved the development life cycle through final implementation using Agile methodologies.
- Completed full life-cycle development of Soarian Clinical to P2Sentinel interface.
- Produced SQL Stored Procedures to Extract data and Transform the data into the receiving vendor specifications for hundreds of clients. Used FTP protocols to transfer that data to be used by numerous receiving vendors.

Principal Consultant I

(2015 - March 2016)

Drove resolution of client issues through extensive knowledge of application software and effective project management.

- Led the Custom Services team updating tens of thousands of custom programs for ICD-10 regulatory requirements.
- Worked within the Model development team creating SQL stored procedures for the initial release of the Millennium core data updates for Business Intelligence.
- Completed full life-cycle development of Soarian Clinical to Fair Warning systems custom interface for over 20 clients.

Siemens Medical Solutions Malvern, PA

2000 - 2015

Principal Consultant I

(2002 - February 2015)

Served as a subject matter expert, drove analysis of technical requests, and estimated effort for projects.

• Conducted full life-cycle software development in multiple software environments including mainframe-based Invision Clinicals, Invision Patient Accounting, and Signature; as well as client-server based Soarian Clinicals, Soarian Financials, and Soarian Scheduling.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Pennsylvania,

Philadelphia, PA

A 24-week intensive program focused on technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Business Administration in Computer Science: Temple University, Philadelphia, PA